M.Tech. (WT – I)                        WAD – I                  Practical Assignment – II

1. Write a PHP script which allows user to enter product code, product name, product price and 
     discount percentage. The program must use a function to calculate discounted amount calculate 
     net pay amount.
2. Write a PHP script file which make your pages have the same look. [Hint: use require]
3. Write a PHP function which ask the user number of tickets to be booked. The function get the no. 
     of booked tickets and create a table based on that which have exactly same rows as number 
     entered by user. The value for rows are booked ticket numbers.
4. Write a function which takes 5 number of input as array from user. Then calculate total and 
     average and display total and average of the 5 numbers.[Hint: use & to return multiple values]
5. Write a program to calculate factorial value by using recursive function. The value must be 
     entered by user.
6. Create a class Vehicle having attributes VID, ModelNo and Mileage( per litere). Write operations 
     to calculate cost per Km by asking price of fuel from user. Implement all the attributes and 
     operations for the class.
7. Create a class Car which is child class of the class Vehicle. Add the operation maintenance for 
     car class. The maintenance class has a property to calculate cost to maintain a car in good 
     condition for a month. Write a function which provides the total maintenance cost of a car for the 
     year.
8. Using question 6,7 take input from user for three cars maintenance. Add these records into text 
     file. Calculate most economical car and display car details.
9. Make Exception handling for Question No. 8.
10. Write an PHP script which allows user to enter product Name, Quantity and Price. Based on the 
     price and quantity calculate cost for each item and total cost. Make validation that the Quantity 
     and Price must not be blanks and they are must be >=0. If any user enter violates the rule, make 
     appropriate exception handling.
11. Explain with example following functions for array:
     i. sort ii. Asort iii. Ksort iv. Rsort v. arsort vi. Krsort vii. Shuffle viii. Arrayreverse ix.
     Arraypush x. arraypop xi. Each xii. Current xiii. Reset xiv. End xv. Next xvi. Pos xvii. Prev 
     xvii. Arraywalk xviii. Count xix. Sizeof xx. Arraycountvalues xxi. Extract
12. Explain following string manipulation functions:
     i. isset ii. Empty iii. Substr iv. Strops v. stripos vi. Strrpos vii. Strripos viii. Strreplace
     xi. strireplace x. ltrim xi. Rtrim xii. Trim xiii. Strpad xiv. Lcfirst xv. Ucfirst xvi. Ucword 
     xvii. strtolower xviii. Strtoupper xix. Strrev xx. Strshuffle xxi. Strrepeat xxii. Explode
     xxiii. implode xxiv. Addslashes xxv. Stripslashes xxvi. Chr xxvii. Ord xxviii. Strtok     xxix.
     strcmp xxx. Strcasecmp xxxi. Strnatcasecmp xxxii. Strnatcmp xxxiii. Strlen        xxxiv. strstr
     xxxv. Strchr xxxvi. Strchr xxxvii. Strrchr xxxviii. Stristr xxxix. Strreplace
     xxxx. substrreplace















                                       Page 1 of 1

